Uh yeah, we're talking about coding
agents a fair bit now and I think one of
the next steps as soon as autonomy kind
of kicks in and we realize actually we
don't need to nurse or babysit agents
quite as constantly as we would an
assistant uh in that you know more chat
format, we can kind of fire and forget a
little bit and then wait till we see
responses. we think about fleets of
coding agents, the ability to actually
orchestrate uh a number of coding agents
and there are a number of reasons why we
might do that. Um, one really strong way
of being able to do something like this
is open hands and we're really really
proud to have the uh founder and CEO of
Open Hands, Robert Brennan, here to uh
to talk us through it. So, please
welcome on stage Robert Brennan.
[music] Thanks so much. [applause]
All right, thank you all for having me
today. I'm really excited to be here.
[snorts]
Um, so today we're going to talk about
how to not just run like a single coding
agent on your workstation, but to manage
a whole fleet of agents potentially
running in the cloud.
Uh, a little bit about me. Uh, my name
is Robert Brennan. I'm the CEO and
co-founder at OpenHands. I've been
working in developer tooling for uh,
over a decade now. uh mainly around open
source um and uh have been working in
natural language processing for for even
longer than that. Uh it's been really
fun to for me to see over the last few
years those two worlds really collide uh
as large language models have gotten
exceptionally good at writing code.
[snorts]
Um I think it's it's uh pretty uh easy
to assume now software development is
changing. I think we've all seen our
jobs change quite a bit over the last
couple years. Uh I know my day-to-day
workflow is radically different than it
was uh 2 years ago. Uh now I would say
literally every line of of code that I
write goes through open hands. Uh I
never open an IDE anymore. Uh it's a
very very different way of working, very
fun way of working. Uh but one thing I
want to convince you of is that we're
still in the first innings of this
change. Um a the technology itself is
getting better and better over time.
agents are able to take on more and more
of of the work involved in software
engineering and especially more and more
of the toil. Um, but it's also uh I
would say even if the technology were
frozen today, there are still um there's
a lot that's possible with the
technology that we haven't really
cracked yet. Um uh both from like a
cultural standpoint and an
organizational standpoint. And so what I
want to show to you today is what we're
seeing uh the most effective, most elite
uh agentic engineering teams doing with
agents at scale. [snorts]
Uh a little bit about how we got here.
Um so I would say in the in the early
days of LLMs, you could get them to
write little snippets of code, you know,
completely uh unaware of what's going on
in your codebase, but you could say,
"Hey, write me bubble sort. Um you know,
do it in this programming language." And
they were pretty good at writing code.
Uh this was helpful. It was uh you know
kind of a neat supplement to Stack
Overflow. Um and then pretty soon after
that we got uh what I call like context
aware code generation. So things like
GitHub Copilot where it's plugged into
your IDE uh and it can see you know a
bit of context about you know where
you're editing, what you're working on
um and generate code that's relevant to
your codebase. So you can see the little
robot gets eyes all of a sudden. Um uh I
would say over the last 18 months or so
we've seen agents come about uh really
over the last year uh with the with the
invention of tool calling and sonnet
3.5. [snorts] Um and this uh basically
got agents to not just write code but
they could run the code that they wrote
Google an error message that comes out
do that entire interloop of development.
And what we're seeing emerge now is
basically using parallel agents uh in
tandem with each other to do larger
scale work than a single agent could
take on.
Uh a little bit about how this has
looked from like a market landscape. Uh
we really again started on the left with
these like plugins maybe AI power IDEs.
Uh we've now moved on to local agents. I
think your your median developer is kind
of starting to adopt things like cloud
code. Um the next generation uh where
your early adopters are now is really
cloud agents. agents that have their own
sandboxes in the cloud. They might be
driven through a web uh API, a guey,
something like that. Um you can get a
lot more agents working in parallel that
way. Uh and then what we're really
seeing with the the top 1% of uh early
adopters here um what we're calling
agentic engineers are folks who are
orchestrating multiple agents that can
work together uh and play off of each
other. We call this agent orchestration.
Uh a little bit about what orchestration
is useful for. It's not useful for every
single task. you're not going to want
to, you know, have multiple agents
swarming on a bug fix or a new feature.
Um, but there are a lot of tasks in
software engineering that are highly
automatable and very repeatable. Um, so
things like code maintenance and tech
debt really u make up the bulk of this.
Um, so a lot of things like uh
remediating open source uh
vulnerabilities, uh, automating your
documentation or release notes, um,
bringing apps up to date, so like
migrating from an old version of Java to
a new version of Java, um, moving from
like, uh, you know, one React state
management system to another. Um, a lot
of like tech debt oriented things like
we've used it to add type annotations
throughout our Python codebase. These
are all like toiley tasks that
developers don't want to do. They're a
little bit too big for like just you
know tell cloud code to just migrate
your entire app from Angular to React.
It's going to fall down. Um but it is
the sort of thing you can get a fleet of
agents working on together.
Uh again this is not something we expect
uh folks to use for every task and it's
not something we expect every engineer
to use. Um what we're seeing is that you
know every developer is using one agent
locally to do one thing at a time.
That's great. That's a that's a very um
meaningful lift in productivity. uh
something like 20 to 30% uh per
developer for writing code. Uh but what
we're seeing is that some engineers are
able to identify those uh big chunks of
work, big chunks of toil that their
teams are doing uh and use agents for
select repeatable tasks to get even
better productivity gains. Another order
of magnitude of productivity gains for
things like migrating code bases,
automating CVE resolution, things like
that.
[snorts]
A little bit about what this workflow
looks like when you do have multiple
agents. Uh for a single agent, it's
fairly simple, right? It's it's very
similar to the interloop of development.
You prompt the agent, the agent makes
some changes. Uh you check the output,
make sure the code changes look good.
You maybe you run the application, etc.
Uh and then maybe you prompt the agent
again to drive it a little further or
you accept it and say this is good.
[snorts]
When you've got multiple agents, it gets
a little bit trickier. Uh you need to
start by decomposing the task into
nicely separable uh pieces. And we'll
talk a little bit about how to do that.
Well, uh then you can get an agent
running on each of the pieces. Uh and
you're going to run an agent loop for
each one of those. And then at the end,
you'll have to collate the output
together uh into a single pull request
or get it all merged into your codebase
together.
Uh importantly, there's still a human in
the loop for each of these agent loops,
right? You have to verify that each one
has done its job correctly. Um so I like
to tell folks that you shouldn't expect
to if you're if you're orchestrating
multiple agents on a big task, you
shouldn't expect it to be 100%
automated. It should be something like
90% automation and then 10% human in the
loop human checking the output. Um so
there's still a lot of human work
involved here.
Uh a bit about you know more tactically
what this looks like uh in terms of
working with git. Um typically what we
what we see folks do is start a branch.
Um they'll add some kind of context to
that branch about what is this project
we're working on. Are we migrating
Angular to React? Uh are we you know
migrating from an old version of Java to
a new one?
um you know add that in uh in the open
hands world we'll call it a microaggent.
There's also agents.mmd. Uh you might be
familiar with cursor rules, things like
that. But you can check a file into the
repository explaining to the agents
what's going on here. Uh you might want
to get some scaffolding in place. Uh and
then you can send off your agents. Um
each agent should create a pull request
into that branch you've created and
that's where you're going to accumulate
work over time. [snorts] Um I would say
something around three to five
concurrent agents is where my brain
starts to break. Uh I've seen folks do
dozens um especially for like very small
uh repeatable tasks. Um uh but you can
just kind of uh iteratively merge those
PRs into that v1 refactor branch. Uh and
then once you're done, once all the
agents are finished, you validated all
their output, you can merge that into
the main branch.
Uh a little bit about like how to
properly decompose tasks. Uh you're
looking for tasks that are can basically
be one-shotted, right? something you you
reasonably confident, you can give it to
an agent and the agent's going to
complete the task. Maybe you need one
more turn of the loop and you prompt it
again, but you should be fairly
confident the agent's going to be able
to take this on. Uh you also want it to
be something that can fit into a single
PR. Uh and you want to have like a clear
uh set of dependencies between the
tasks. You want to know, okay, once I
get a done, then I can do B, C, and D in
parallel, and then I'm going to do E
once those are all done. Uh having that
parallelization is super helpful. It
means that uh it's going to move a lot
faster if you're trying to do everything
serially. Uh it's going to take a long
time or you have to wait for agent A to
finish before you start agent B. So the
more you can parallelize uh the better.
Very similar to like managing a team of
engineers. You might have one person
working on front end, one person working
on back end. Uh something like that. Uh
and you also want something you can
quickly verify or reject, right? You
want to be uh if you can know that like,
hey, if CI/CD is passing, the thing did
its job. I can trust it. It's okay.
That's the best. Um, maybe it's
something you need to click around a UI,
make sure the app still works. Um, but
you want to be able to quickly, you
know, be able to look at the code, look
at CI/CD, and understand like, did it do
the thing or did it not?
Uh, you'll also want to think about how
you're going to share context between
these agents. Usually, as you're working
on a big task like this, you're going to
learn things as you go. Um, and you need
to make sure that that information gets
shared across all the different agents
that are working here. Uh there are a
few different ways to do this. The most
naive approach would be for a human to
just like type into a chat window, you
know, to each agent do XYZ, you know,
use version 1.2 instead of version 1.1.
Um you can use like an agentmd or an
openhands micro agent to share
knowledge. Uh the agents can even update
that themselves automatically. Um or you
can even uh define tool calls that allow
agents to pass messages to each other.
All right, I want to show a bit a bit of
a demo of how this works. Um, so I've uh
I've built a a uh a script using the
open hands SDK that's going to look at a
GitHub repository, detect all the CVEEs,
uh you know, all the open source
vulnerabilities that are in that
repository, and then send off a fleet of
agents for each of the individual
vulnerabilities to solve that
vulnerability. I'm [snorts] going to
kick it off on the left side here
because it'll it'll take a minute. Um
u so I'm going to scan this this Polaris
repo. Um, and I'll talk a little bit
about how this is working uh, as it
runs.
So, essentially what we're going to do
is we've set up one agent. You can see
it's scanning now. Uh, that's going to
uh, look at this repo and figure out how
am I going to scan for vulnerabilities.
You know, it can look at what
programming language is being used. It
can um, uh, see is there a Docker file?
Maybe I can build the image and scan
that. Um, this is the really nice thing
about agents is that, you know, it
doesn't have to have very explicit
instructions on how am I going to scan
for vulnerabilities. It can kind of
figure its own thing out. And you can
see the agent here is, uh, you know,
it's installing Trivy. Uh, we're going
to see it run Trivy to like gather a
list of vulnerabilities.
And then where the real power comes in
is that once we get that list of
vulnerabilities, for every single
vulnerability, we can send off a new
agent to solve that one. Um, this is
much better than say uh having a single
agent trying to solve them all. uh
because one there might be just like a
ton of uh if there's if there's a
hundred vulnerabilities it might get
lost. Uh you've probably seen agents get
lazy it'll solve three and then say okay
now go hire a team of people to do the
rest. Um so it's really nice to separate
it out and this way too if if we have
you know 100 vulnerabilities say uh if I
can get 90 of those merged and 10 of
them get stuck that's still a big big
win right we've still resolved 90% of
the vulnerabilities here. So
parallelizing this makes it go faster
and uh means that we can get to partial
successes uh really quickly. Uh so each
of these uh sub aents is going to
research the solvability of the
vulnerability handed to it. Uh it's
going to update the relevant dependency,
maybe fix any breaking API changes that
are in the code. Um and then open up a
poll request for us to merge. Um so you
can see our our scanner here has found
three vulnerabilities. Uh and we've
kicked off three different agents. Each
one is going to solve a different a
different CVE.
Uh a bit about what this looks like uh
in pseudo code. I'll make this bigger.
Um this is using the open hands SDK to
actually initialize the agents. Um you
can see we give the agent a terminal
that it can use. We give it a file
editor so it can mess with the codebase.
Uh and we give it a task tracker so it
can like plan and and uh execute on that
plan. Uh, and then we just send it a
message saying, "Hey, scan this repo for
CVES, use Trivy, put your results in
this JSON file."
Uh, and then we can, uh, read up that
JSON file, grab each vulnerability, and
then inside of a for loop, just send off
a new agent saying, "Solve the CVE ID."
Uh, what's really nice about the
Openhands SDK is that we can run each of
these agents inside of their own
workspace, inside of their own like
developer workstation, so that each one
gets a nice sandbox. they're not
stepping on each other's toes trying to
edit the same code. Uh things like that.
So they each get like their own, it's
almost like they're individual
developers working on their own laptop.
Um and you can get these running not
only where the script is running, um but
you can run them inside of Docker
containers. Like the script can connect
to a Docker container or can connect to
a Kubernetes pod. So these agents can
really be running anywhere either
locally or in the cloud. [snorts]
U I can show a little bit about what
this looks like in the actual GitHub
repo.
See,
uh, this here is kind of pseudo code,
but you can see we've got prompts for
the scanner, explaining exactly how to,
uh, let's make this a little bigger. Uh,
explaining exactly how to go about
scanning a GitHub repo. Uh we've got
prompts for uh the solvers explaining,
you know, exactly uh here's how to solve
a particular vulnerability. Here's how
you should investigate. Here's the
format of the poll request we want you
to open up. So it's all uh you know,
neatly patterned according to our style
guide, the way that we work, the way
that we want to solve these CVEes. Um,
and then we've got
a bunch of Python code that basically
just invokes the uh open hands SDK in
order to drive this whole workflow.
Uh, let's see where the uh where the
scanners are at. Uh, so you can see as
each of them are working here,
you know, they're moving through the
codebase. Each one is uh, you know,
installing new packages with mpm,
looking for the packages they're
supposed to be solving inside of
package.json. JSON. Um, we can let this
run for a minute or two. It looks like
they're starting to uh finish up. Uh, we
should see a poll request come out for
each of these, but in the meantime, I'm
happy to take questions from the
audience.
>> Back.
>> Always right at the back, isn't it?
Um, so is OpenHands doing anything
uniquely to mitigate code conflicts? Cuz
if you have like 12 PRs that are raised,
then how are you managing that? If
there's changes that over overlap same
file.
>> Yeah, it's a great question. Uh, I would
say uh one thing we've noticed is that
agents are exceptionally good at fixing
merge conflicts. uh I would say actually
better than humans uh because they'll
actually look at uh the intention behind
the original changes and you know what
their changes were and try to merge
them. So it can it can become a pain to
like do another turn of the loop if the
first change gets merged and there's
merge conflicts in this other PR. Um but
uh we often will put into a script like
this uh uh just kind of like watching
the PR if merge conflicts crop up or
there's a CI/CD failure you just send
the agent another message saying you
know please please fix the merge
conflicts. Uh it's a fairly easy thing
to automate.
>> Um how does open hands work with uh
local models and um what is the smallest
model that open hands works well with?
>> Yeah, great question. Um so we uh we do
work well with local models. We're
totally model agnostic. Um we released a
model uh with Mistral called Devstcrol
um which which was trained especially to
work well with open hands. I would say
that's the best like small model that
you're that you can run locally. Uh
Quinn 3 also works very well if you can
get it running locally. Um uh I believe
Kimmy 2 works very well. Um so yeah, we
we actually published benchmarks for all
the different models and how they how
well they work with open hands.
>> Uh I think we released [snorts]
uh I think we released everything from a
3 billion to a 32 billion with Devstrol.
Uh the three billion, you know, you can
imagine is not amazing, but it it works.
>> Pardon my lack of imagination. You said
you're not working like in an IDE
anymore. You're more working in open
hands. Could you describe a little bit
about that process for like building the
agents and you know like this is really
interesting to see, but I'm trying to
get my head around, okay, where did you
start and go I need a CVE fleet of
agents? How did that come about?
>> Yeah. Um I would say my my workflow
uh mainly switched over to using our web
app. Um so to build the CVE demo for
instance uh I would just connect it to
the repo and then tell it exactly what I
wanted it to build. Uh what I wanted it
to do. Uh so one thing I was working on
ahead of this is like uh use the
openhand software agent SDK
to um
uh plum in the GitHub token as a secret.
And so this is uh like a very you know
standard familiar way of using an agent
right if you've used Devon or if you've
used um uh Jules something like that u
right you're chatting with an agent we
can see it working on the right side of
the screen um you can see it has a a
terminal and we've got a VS code here um
so this is kind of like my daily driver
u I think where open hands really is
different is when you start working with
uh the SDK
um
uh which really allows you to start
driving agents with code, right? So, if
you're starting to build these very
repeatable workflows like you know you
want to be able to solve CVES throughout
your entire company's codebase uh in
some kind of uh you know patterned
manner, you can write Python code that
drives a very particular workflow. It's
going to open up PRs that match a very
particular pattern. It's going to
prioritize criticals over anything else
etc. Um you can start writing Python
code that really drives these agents um
in a more deterministic way, right? It
allows you to kind of combine the the
non-determinism of the agents with these
more deterministic workflows that patch
those those nondeterministic loops
together.
>> Yesterday we heard about uh claude flow.
When would you recommend open hands over
cloud flow? Um or are they really two
different beasts that I'm not quite got
my head wrapped around yet?
>> Uh I'm not I'm not familiar with cloud
flow actually. Anybody want to give me a
quick
>> agent orchestration? Okay. Yeah.
>> So maybe geneneralally your thoughts on
agent swarming solutions.
>> Yeah.
>> You repeat the question just for that.
>> So yeah the the um so cloudflow is a way
to run multiple cloud codes um and a you
know swarming swarming agents. I would
say one um what you're want going to
want to do I've seen a lot of people
like run multiple quad codes like in
T-Mox with like different different
panels right um that works reasonably
well for a few agents at once but
they're all because they're all running
on the same workstation uh potentially
um you know trying to install different
versions of different things they might
step on each other's toes a bit to give
each one separation so getting like um
sandboxes you know running in the cloud
somewhere you know in a Kubernetes
cluster or at least in Docker containers
on your workstation
super helpful. Um, and I would say like
in general, uh, you can graduate to
these fleets of agents when you have a
task that's super repeatable. Um,
something something where, uh, you know,
you're going to be doing this over and
over and over again and it doesn't make
sense for you to be like typing in
prompts to different chat windows and
instead you want to have some kind of
deterministic codebased flow.
So um I realize this is a little bit
tangential but uh obviously for a
repeatable task it might make sense to
have many agents working on it in
parallel. How do you think about this
for like new feature development where
maybe you need a spec maybe it's not
quite as deterministic? Um are you using
the SDK to orchestrate stuff like that?
Are you using one chat window at a time?
Like what's the process that you go for
>> new feature development? I typically
will open up a few chat windows, right?
Um, I'll have one agent working on front
end, one on back end, something like
that. Um, because it's not it's not
super repeatable. Um, you know, if
you're going to be doing uh uh like
something hyper repeatable where it's
like every new feature is going to be a
new page in your React app and a new API
endpoint, maybe you can start to build
some uh like boilerplate code that will
help you drive the same workflow over
and over again. Um, but I think this
this stuff really shines more for the
tech debt, more the code maintenance
type tasks. Good question. Other
questions?
In the meantime, we can see we got three
new poll requests from our agents. Uh
each one opening uh you know closing a
different CVE. Um so nice to see it
actually actually worked. [snorts]
[music]
Thank you.
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]